Naruto Shippuden, Sasuke's Story:
Sunrise, Part 2: Coliseum
(カカシ)「起爆人間に遭遇。
"Encountered Exploding Humans."
独自に調査を行う
了承されたし」か。
"Will investigate independently.
Please approve."
(カカシ)
お前の旅は いつまで続くんだ。
Just how long will
your journey continue?
Sasuke, where are you going?
(チノ)サスケちゃん
どこに行くの？
You're Sasuke Uchiha, right?
(ノワキ)キミだよね
うちはサスケ。
(チノ)誇り高き
うちは一族唯一の生き残り。
The lone survivor of
the exalted Uchiha Clan.
(ノワキ)ゆうべの写輪眼を見て
すぐにわかったよ。
I knew it the moment I saw
your Sharingan last night.
これから どこ行くの？
Where are you going now?
(サスケ)お前たちには関係ない。
That has nothing to do with you.
関係なくないよ！
It does involve us!
アミノさんは
おいしいご飯作ってくれたよ。
Amino…
…made us yummy meals.
優しかったよ。
She was kind.
風心ってやつ
捜すんだよね？
You're going to look for
that Fuushin guy, right?
えっ え～
そいつでしょ？
But isn't he the one who changed
Amino and the others
アミノさんたちを
なんとか人間にしちゃったの！
into the human something
or other, right?
私らも ついてくよ。
We're going with you.
何かの役に立てると思う。
うん。
I think we may be able to help.
(チノ)そんなふうに お前らなんか
必要ないって態度とられると→
And don't give us that look that says
"I don't need you guys!"
That will only make us more determined!
反抗したくなるんだけど！
ねぇ サスケちゃんってば！
Sasuke dear, are you listening?!
あれ？
どうでもいいが
その呼び方はやめろ。
I don't care what you do.
Just stop calling me that.
私は サスケちゃんより
年上だと思うよ。
I figure I'm older than you,
Sasuke dear.
So I can call you "dear."
だから
ちゃんづけでもいいじゃん。
年上？ お前が？
エッヘン！
Older? You?
Ahem!
そんなにか。
By that much?
What do you mean by "that much"?
何が そんなになのかな？
サスケちゃんさ
見た目や思い込みで→
Sasuke dear, it's not good
to judge people by their looks
人を判断しないほうが
いいと思うよ。
or by your impression of them.
You shouldn't judge people
((イタチ : 見た目や思い込みだけで→
人を判断しないほうがいいですよ。
by their looks or
by your impression of them.
HIDDEN LEAF POLICE FORCE
Are you going to join too, Big Brother?
兄さんも ここに入るの？
(イタチ)さあ どうかなあ？
HIDDEN LEAF POLICE FORCE
I wonder…
You should! When I'm older…
そうしなよ
大きくなったら→
俺も警務部隊に
入るからさ！
I'm going to join
the Leaf Police Force too!
許せ サスケ
これで最後だ。
Forgive me, Sasuke…
This is the last time.
No matter what happens from now,
I will love you always.
お前が これからどうなろうと→
(俺は お前を
ずっと愛している))
(チノ)…ちゃん サスケちゃん！
Sasuke dear!
By the way… Have you been back to
the Hidden Leaf Village, Sasuke dear?
そういえばさ サスケちゃんは
木ノ葉隠れの里に帰ってんの？
アッハ また無視かい。
What? Ignoring me again?
What about reviving the Uchiha Clan?
You're the lone survivor, right?
うちはの復興とか
あるんじゃないの？
生き残り１人なんでしょ？
もしも～し
聞こえてますか～？
Hello! Are you there, Sasuke?!
Chino, stop it.
チノ やめとけ。
あんたは どっちの味方なのよ
だいたい ノワキはね…。
Whose side are you on anyway?
You know, you…
Hey, where are we going?
ところでさ
どこに向かってんの？
また無視かい。
ん。
Ignoring me again!
I mean…
だって～！
おい。
Hey.
私の名前は
おいじゃないんですけどぉ？
My name isn't "hey"!
風心を捜すのかと聞いたな？
そのとおりだ。
You asked if I'm going to
look for Fuushin.
The answer is yes.
え？
Huh?
それが 今
俺のやるべきことだ。
That's what I should do right now.
A-Any ideas on where to look?
アテはあるんだよね？
起爆人間を生み出せるのは
血継限界くらいのものだ。
The only thing that can create
an Exploding Human
is a Kekkei Genkai.
H-Hey, Sasuke dear…
Hold on a minute…
あっ あ～
ちょっと サスケちゃん待ってよ！
(チノ)で あの
いかにも怪しげな洞窟の中に→
You think you'll find him inside
that really scary-looking cave?
そのアテがいるの？
Ignoring me again!
また無視 …ん。
(ヤマト)サスケ だね？
You're Sasuke, right?
(ヤマト)僕は ヤマトと
名乗っておこうか。
You can call me Yamato.
Since you're watching over this place,
it must mean that Orochimaru is here.
監視がいるということは
大蛇丸は ここにいるんだな？
O-Orochimaru? You mean that—?!
お 大蛇丸って あの!?
What's the purpose of your visit?
用件を聞かせてくれるかい？
大蛇丸に
接触しようとする人間を→
I can't allow just anyone through
to see Orochimaru.
素通りさせる訳には
いかないんでね。
木ノ葉で起きた
起爆人間の襲撃。
Regarding the Exploding Humans
that attacked the Hidden Leaf…
その首謀者に
つながる情報を→
It's possible Orochimaru may have
information about the perpetrator.
大蛇丸が
持っている可能性がある。
Did you send word about this
to Lord Sixth?
６代目には この件
連絡したの？
結果が出れば
報告するつもりだ。
I intend to, if I get results.
う～ん 逐一 途中経過を
送ってもらったほうが→
It would be much easier for us
to coordinate things,
こっちとしても
連携とりやすいんだけどな。
if you'd send us progress reports…
でも…。
However…
木ノ葉のために
動いてるんだよね？
You're doing this all for the sake
for the Hidden Leaf, right?
ああ。
Yeah…
はあ 仕方がないな。
Then there's nothing else to say.
６代目には
僕から報告しておくよ。
I'll send Lord Sixth a report.
Remember, we're comrades.
仲間だからね。
I'm sure Mr. Kakashi also taught you
the importance of trust and teamwork.
信頼と チームワークの大切さは→
キミも カカシさんに
教わっただろう？
すまない。
Thank you…
(大蛇丸)久しぶりね サスケ君。
It's been a long time, Sasuke.
おもしろそうな友達
連れてるじゃない。
You've brought some
interesting-looking friends with you.
雷光団の風心を知っているか？
Do you know Fuushin
of the Lightning Gang?
あら 挨拶もなし？
What? Not even a greeting?
You're as blunt as ever.
相変わらず唐突ね。
知っていることがあるなら
すべて話せ。
Tell me everything you know.
それが
人に ものを頼む態度かしら？
Is that any way to ask
a person something?
さっさとしろ。
Hurry up.
Fuushin possesses a Kekkei Genkai…
風心は血継限界の持ち主で→
I believe he originally was a member
of En Oyashiro's guard unit.
もとは
御屋城エンの護衛団にいたはずよ。
En Oyashiro?
御屋城エン？
He's not affiliated with any group.
どこにも属さない男でね→
忍でありながら
武器商人でもある男よ。
Even though he's a shinobi,
he's an arms trader.
カネさえ積めば 誰にでも
武器を売りさばくもんだから→
He'll sell weapons to anyone
for the right price,
so he's known as
the "Merchant of Death."
死の商人なんて呼ばれていたわ。
He's amassed a huge fortune
during his lifetime.
一代で莫大な財を築いた
やり手ね。
どこにいる？
さあ。
Where is he?
Who knows…
彼は私以上に
アジトを持っているようだから。
He has a hideout
even better hidden than mine.
I think finding him
will be very difficult.
捜すとなると
難しいかもしれないわね。
その難しいことも
あんたなら簡単にできるはずだ。
For you, even the difficult is easy.
ククク… 信頼されているのかしら？
Does that mean you trust me?
そうね
どこにいるかはわからないけど→
Well, I don't know where to find him,
but I can lure him out.
おびき寄せることはできるわ。
でも それには 面倒なことが
あるかもしれないわよ？
However…
that may cause a few problems.
Why do you think I came here?
何のために
ここまで来たと思っている。
らしくないわね。
How unlike you…
やるべきことを やるだけだ。
I'm just doing what I have to.
クク… 風を感じるわ。
I sense the wind.
ちょっと待ってて
準備に時間がかかるから。
Wait here.
It will take some time to prepare.
サスケちゃん！
Sasuke dear!
I didn't know that
you knew Orochimaru.
大蛇丸と知り合いだなんて
聞いてないよ。
I don't recall ever telling you.
言った覚えもない。
むぅ…。
(香燐)サスケ！ アハッ なんだよ～。
Sasuke!
Hey! Why didn't you
let me know you're coming?
来るなら来るって… ん？
サスケちゃん…。
Sasuke dear…
サスケ… ちゃん？
"Sasuke dear"?!
What? Is she your girlfriend, Sasuke?
(水月)ん？ なに？
その子 サスケの彼女？
こ こんな へちゃむくれが→
You mean, that ugly hag?
か… かか… 彼女とか
ありえねえだろうが！
Hey! Who're you calling ugly?!
ちょっと！
へちゃむくれって誰のこと!?
Sasuke, say it's not true!
サスケ 嘘だと言ってくれよ。
It's not true.
嘘だ。
ほ～。
フン どうだろうね 今の慌てっぷり。
You should've seen
the look of panic on your face.
Shut up!
黙れ！ お前がくだんねえこと
言うからじゃねえか。
If it weren't for that
big mouth of yours!
That's no excuse for looking like…
(水月)だからって
世界の終わりみたいな…。
(重吾)久しぶりだな。
うん。
- It's been awhile.
- it's the end of the world!
You've been continuing your travels?
ずっと旅を続けているのか？
あぁ。
Yeah.
木ノ葉には帰ってねえの？
You haven't gone back to
Hidden Leaf Village?
See, you're worried sick
about Sasuke.
やっぱ サスケのことが
気になってしようがないんじゃん。
You're really getting on my nerves!
マジで うっせえな てめえは！
あんたたち うるさいわよ。
Quiet, you guys.
準備が整ったわ。
行きましょうか。
I'm ready. Shall we go?
大蛇丸様
どこか出かけるんですか？
Lord Orochimaru, are you going out?
サスケ君と ちょっと海にね。
Sasuke and I are going to the sea.
Huh?!
えっ えぇ～っ！ サスケと海に…。
The ocean? With Sasuke?
You all will stay and mind the fort.
(大蛇丸)あなたたちは留守番よ。
The sea with Lord Orochimaru?
I can't quite picture it.
大蛇丸様と海って
なんか想像つかないっすね。
Wait, that's news to me too.
待て 俺も初耳だ。
To be more precise,
a solitary island in the sea.
正確に言えば 海に浮かぶ孤島よ。
その島に金持ちの娯楽場があるの。
There's a paradise for the wealthy there.
そこに御屋城がいるのか？
And that's where En Oyashiro is?
If he takes the bait.
エサに食いつけば… ね。
- Nowaki.
- Yeah.
ノワキ。
ああ。
サスケ～。
Sasuke…
Bleh!
ベーッ！
あ？
What's with that girl?
Wanna fight?
なんだ あのアマ やんのか こら！
あ～ もう 面倒くさいな。
Oh, what a drag.
Sasuke working for
the sake of strangers…
(水月)
サスケが他人のために動くとはね。
襲われたのは木ノ葉の里なんだ。
The Hidden Leaf was attacked…
They're not strangers…
他人というわけでもないだろう。
But he didn't return to the village.
でもさ 木ノ葉には
帰ってないんでしょ。
I wonder if it's hard
for him to go back?
やっぱ いづらいのかな？
Don't you guys get it?
(香燐)わかってねえな。
The big war might be over,
でかい戦争がなくなったって
やばいヤローはいくらでもいんだろ。
but there are still lots of
dangerous characters lurking around.
As long as Sasuke has those eyes…
サスケがあの目を持っている以上→
shinobi will continue
to attack the village.
里を襲う忍も出てくるだろ。
So by showing that Sasuke Uchiha
isn't in Hidden Leaf Village
だから うちはサスケは
木ノ葉にはおらず→
and he's still journeying
around the world,
常に世界を放浪してるって
まわりに示すことで→
里に被害が及ぶ可能性も
減るってわけ。
it lessens the possibility that
the village will be harmed.
So then,
Sasuke has to continue traveling?
それなら サスケは
ずっと旅を続けんの？
That might be it.
(重吾)そうなるのかもしれないな。
しかし 木ノ葉崩しに
四代目風影暗殺…。
Still…
The fact that you, the one who instigated
the destruction of the Hidden Leaf,
他にも さまざまな大罪を
犯してきたあんたが→
the assassination of the Fourth Kazekage
and countless other horrific crimes,
こうやって自由に動けるってのも
奇妙な話だな。
can still move around freely
is quite astonishing.
(大蛇丸)ククッ…。
自由ではないわよ。
I'm not free.
それに サスケ君がそれを言う？
And who are you to talk, Sasuke?
あなただって本来なら
投獄されてた身の上でしょ。
By all rights, you should be locked up.
まあ 第四次忍界大戦の
戦犯の一人 カブトだって今や→
But even Kabuto,
one of the war criminals from
the Fourth Ninja World War
孤児院の院長なんだけどね。
is now the director of an orphanage…
カブトが…。
もっとも私に比べれば→
Kabuto is?
Of course, compared to me,
カブトのほうが 悪に走る確率は
低いでしょうけど。
the likelihood that Kabuto will
resort to evil is lower.
なぜ そう言い切れる？
How can you be so sure?
フフッ うちはイタチの力を
信用できないの？
Don't you trust the power
of Itachi Uchiha?
(大蛇丸)私もあなたも
そしてカブトも→
You and I, and Kabuto
could just be insurance…
常識で対処できないことが
起きたときのための→
in case something happens that cannot
be countered with common sense.
保険かもしれないわね。
保険？
Insurance?
どの時代も異端児は現れるもの。
In every era, a maverick appears.
そのとき 私たちのような→
When that happens, there may be
a need for people like us
非人道的な力が必要な場合もある。
who possess powers
considered to be inhuman.
正しさだけでは
守れないものもあるんだから。
There are things that cannot be
protected by righteousness alone.
だったら
うまく飼いならしたほうが→
If that's the case, keeping us around
like pets might be mutually beneficial.
お互いのためになることも…。
でも まあ あなたのお友達は→
But…
your friend would never even
think of such a tactic.
そんな駆け引き
一切 頭にないでしょうけどね。
Probably not.
そうだろうな。
(大蛇丸)さて 見えてきたわね。
There…
You can see it in the distance.
ここ どこ？
Where are we?
This is an island that
you can't find on any map.
ここは地図にも載らない孤島よ。
はぁ…。
さあ 行きましょ。
Oh…
Let's go.
なんなの ここ？
What is this place?
コロシアムと呼ばれてるわ。
コロシアム？
It's called the Coliseum.
Coliseum?
ご来場の皆々様 楽しんで
いただいてますでしょうか？
Is everyone enjoying themselves so far?
[マイク]勝者に栄光 敗者に絶望！
Honors to the victor!
Despair to the vanquished!
ルールはご存じ 自分の手札と
相手の手札を戦わせるだけ！
As you know, the rules are simple!
The one with your ID tag goes up against
one with another person's ID tag.
そして 勝ったほうが どちらも
手に入れることができる→
And the winner is whoever manages
to take his opponent's ID tag…
弱肉強食シンプルスタイルと
なっております！
Simply put, it's a survival match!
どういうことだ 大蛇丸。
What's going on, Orochimaru?
あの説明どおり
ここにいる金持ち連中は→
You heard the explanation.
The wealthy patrons here pit their shinobi
against shinobi employed by others.
お抱えの忍を戦わせて→
The losing shinobi becomes theirs.
勝ったら相手の忍を
手に入れることができるのよ。
それでは 本日のセミファイナル！
And now, today's semi-final match!
[マイク]まず入場してきたのは
マキビコーポレーション社長→
Now entering the ring…
Wearing the ID tag of President Makibi
of the Makibi Corporation…
マキビ様の手札 黒い稲光 ライメイ！
Raimei, the Black Lightning Flash!
His opponent…
[マイク]対するは ヒメユリカンパニー頭取
ヒメユリ様の手札→
Wearing the ID tag of President Himeyuri
of the Himeyuri Company…
月白の妖炎 スズラン！
Suzuran, the Eerie Flame
of the White Moon!
(大蛇丸)この場は 一種のカジノなの。
This place is like a casino.
それでは まいりましょう！
All right, let's begin!
待ったなし 反則なし
恨みっこなしの一本勝負！
It's now or never, no foul play,
no grudges afterwards…
A single-bout challenge!
Ready?
レディ！
(観客たち)ファイト！
Fight!
趣味の悪い道楽に
つきあっている暇はない。
I don't have time to waste
on sick hobbies.
御屋城エンは どこだ？
(大蛇丸)さぁ？
Where is En Oyashiro?
I wonder…
でも 御屋城エンは→
But this is about the only place
that he'll show up.
ここくらいにしか
姿を見せないのよ。
しかも
欲しい手札がなければ 現れない。
Although, he won't come
if there's no shinobi he wants.
Whoa! Suzuran is down!
おっと！ スズラン ダウン!!
勝利したのは ライメイ！
The winner is Raimei!
[マイク]マキビ社長も大喜び！
President Makibi is overjoyed!
You're useless!
(ヒメユリ)この役立たずが！
Why do you think
I kept you all this time?!
(ヒメユリ)何のために これまで
飼ってきたと思ってるざます！
You ingrate…
この恩知らずめが！
ろくでもない場所だな。
This place is worthless.
(チノ)だったら 助けてあげれば？
Then why don't you help?
被害者にしてみれば
加害者も第三者も一緒。
To a victim, the assailant and
a third party are no different.
自分を救ってくれなかった人たち
それで ひとくくり。
People are no better than the assailant
if they didn't try to help.
ここで行われている金持ちどもの
道楽を止めることなく→
If you only pity the loser and do nothing
to stop the decadence of the rich…
同情的な言葉を
口にするだけのサスケちゃんだって→
you're just as guilty, Sasuke.
共犯者にすぎないよ。
(ノワキ)チノ よせ。
Chino, stop.
チノ！
Chino!
子供に見せるには
刺激が強すぎたかしら？
Was this sight too shocking
for a child?
No, she's older than me.
いや 俺より年上だ。
え…。
What?
[マイク]お待たせしました。
本日のメインイベント！
The wait is finally over!
Now, for the main event!
Wearing En Oyashiro's ID tag is Futsu!
[マイク]まず 現れたのは
御屋城エン様の手札 フツ！
エサに食いついてくれたようね。
It seems he took the bait.
相対しますは 大蛇丸様の手札！
And his opponent will be wearing
Lord Orochimaru's ID tag…
あの五影会談を襲撃した
伝説の男！
The legendary shinobi who attacked
the Five Kage Conference…
The last Uchiha…
Sasuke Uchiha!
最後のうちは うちはサスケだ！
どういうことだ？
What is the meaning of this?!
I told you. Oyashiro will only
appear for something he wants.
言ったでしょ？ 御屋城は
欲しい手札がないと現れないって。
彼ね 血継限界コレクターなの。
He is…a collector of Kekkei Genkai.
血継限界コレクター？
そう。
A collector of Kekkei Genkai?
Yes…
写輪眼を持つサスケ君なら→
As for you with
your Sharingan, Sasuke…
He probably wants
喉から手が出るほどに
欲しいでしょうね。
会場内にいるとわかれば
捜せばいいだけじゃないのか。
(大蛇丸)御屋城は用心深い男で→
姿かたちは もちろん
においを消すのも難なくこなす。
どこにいるかはわからないわ。
ただ 試合終了の手札譲渡の場に
必ず出てくる。
それが ここのしきたりなの。
チッ…。
おっと！ 棄権ですか？
さぁ。
[マイク]来た～！ 満を持して登場
うちはサスケのお出ましだ!!
(エン)あれが うちはサスケ…。
見せてよね 写輪眼。
それでは まいりましょう！
待ったなし 反則なし
恨みっこなしの一本勝負！
レディ！
(観客たち)ファイト！
沸遁 巧霧の術だな。
マ… マキビ社長！
[マイク]救護班… 救護班 呼んで！
《起爆人間？》